glomex.com 2019-04-18

# Privacy Policy | glomex

Privacy Policy for the glomex-Website

This Privacy Policy will inform you about how we process personal data on this website.  
Personal data means any information that refers to an identified or identifiable person. This especially includes information that allows you to be identified, e.g. your name, telephone number, address or email address.

I. Our contact information

The controller in the sense of the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) for this website is glomex GmbH, Dieselstrasse 1, 85774 Unterfoehring.You may contact the Data Protection Officer of glomex with any questions and concerns about data protection directly by email (privacy@glomex.com) or by regular mail by addressing the letter explicitly to the glomex Data Protection Officer.

II. How We Use Your Data

1\. General use of the website

If you contact us, e.g., through our contact form, we will only process your personal data to communicate with you. The legal basis for this is Art. 6(1) Letter b of the GDPR. The data we collect through our contact form will be deleted after the handling of your inquiry is complete, unless we need your inquiry to fulfill other contractual or legal obligations (see Section VII “Storage Duration”)

2\. Registration 

In case you wish to use services which first require the conclusion of a contract, we will ask you to register. Within the scope of registration, we collect personal data necessary for the conclusion and performance of the contract (e.g., first name, last name, email address, if applicable - details on the desired payment method or on the account holder) as well as, if applicable, further data on a voluntary basis. Mandatory fields are marked with an asterisk (*). 

3\. Newsletters

You may subscribe to our newsletter which we will use to regularly inform you about our product and campaign news. You may also unsubscribe from our newsletter at any time. The respective unsubscribe link is included in every newsletter.   
If we receive your e-mail address in connection with our services and you have not objected, we reserve the right to send you regular offers for similar services from our portfolio by e-mail. You can object to this at any time without incurring any costs for you.

Our newsletters use customary market technologies that allow interactions with the newsletters to be measured (e.g., opening the email or activating links). We use this data in pseudonymized form for general statistical assessments and to optimize and further develop our content and customer communication. This is done using small graphics embedded in the newsletters (so-called pixels). Data is only collected pseudonymously and will not be merged with your other personal data. Our newsletter is used to share contents relevant to our clients and to better understand what interests our readers. If you do not want your user behavior to be analyzed, you may unsubscribe from our newsletter or permanently disable the display of graphics in your email program. 

4\. Purposes of processing and legal basis for the processing

We process your personal data for the following purposes and on the following legal bases:

• Provision of this online offer and performance of contract in accordance with our general terms and conditions including billing. (Legal basis: Performance of a contract).

• Personalization of the offer. (Legal basis: Performance of a contract or consent).

• Analysis of the offer for the determination of usage behavior including market research and reach measurement. (Legal basis: Balancing of interests; we have a legitimate interest in analyzing the usage behavior in our online offer for purposes of continuous improvement and to be able to customize it to the interests of our users.

• Dispatch of a newsletter advertising our own offers (Legal basis: consent or balancing of interests; we have a legitimate interest in direct marketing as long as marketing occurs while complying with data protection and fair trade laws).

• Dispatch of a newsletter with the recipient's consent via email or SMS/MMS.   
(Legal basis: Performance of a contract).

• Determination of malfunctions and ensuring of system security including disclosure and tracking of invalid accesses and access attempts to our web server. (Legal basis: fulfilment of our legal obligations in the area of data security and balancing of interests; we have a legitimate interest in the elimination of malfunctions, ensuring of system security and disclosure and tracking of invalid access attempts).

• Protection and defence of our rights. (Legal basis: balancing of interests; we have a legitimate interest in the assertion and defence of our rights.   
Upon request, you may receive information from us regarding the balancing of interests we have made. Simply use the information in the contact section.

III. Cookies

Cookies are little text files that are sent when visiting an internet page and are stored in a user’s browser. In case the respective internet page is accessed once again, the user’s browser sends back the content of the cookies and, thus, allows for the recognition of the user. Certain cookies are automatically deleted upon ending the browser session (so-called session cookies), others are saved for a set time or permanently in the user’s browser and delete themselves thereafter (so-called temporary or persistent cookies).  
Cookies generally do not contain personal data, but merely an online ID. You can deactivate the storage of cookies through your browser settings and you may delete cookies that have already been saved in your browser at any time (see Technical Notes). Please take note that this online offer might not be functional without cookies or the functionality might be reduced.

Please be further advised that refusing to allow the creation of usage profiles partially works through „opt-out cookies“. In case you delete all cookies, an objection might, under certain circumstances, no longer be considered or be valid and would have to be restated. 

1\. Own use of cookies

We use the following types of cookies:

• Cookies strictly necessary for our service 

Some cookies are strictly necessary so we can host our online offer safely. This category includes, e.g.,

o Cookies which serve the purpose of identifying or authenticating our users;  
o Cookies that temporarily store certain user entries (e.g., shopping basket content or content of an online form);  
o Cookies that remember certain user preferences (e.g., search query and language settings);  
o Cookies that store data to ensure the uninterrupted playback of video and audio content

• Analytic Cookies

We use analytic cookies to record and statistically evaluate our users’ usage behavior (e.g., clicked ad banners, visited subpages, search queries asked).

2\. Web Analysis

We need statistical information on how to use our online offering to make it more user-friendly, measure reach and conduct market research. For this purpose we use the following analysis tools. The usage profiles created by the tools using analytic cookies or by evaluating the log files are not merged with personal data. The providers of the tools process data only as a processor according to our instructions and not for their own purposes. The tools either do not use users' IP addresses at all, or truncate them immediately after the survey.

For each tool you will find information about the respective provider and how you can object to the collection and processing of data by the tool. In the case of tools that implement the contradiction by means of opt-out cookies, it should be noted that the opt-out function is device-specific or browser-related and basically only applies to the terminal or browser used. If you use multiple devices or browsers, you must set the opt-out on each individual device and in each browser used.  
In addition, you can prevent the creation of usage profiles for analysis purposes altogether by generally preventing the use of cookies.

2.1 Google Analytics

Our website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland ("Google") for users from the European Economic Area, Switzerland and Liechtenstein and by Google LLC 1600, Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043 ("Google") for all other users.

Google Analytics uses cookies and similar technologies to analyze and improve our website on the basis of your user behavior. Google may transmit the data collected thereby to a server in the US where it will be assessed and saved. For transmissions of personal data to the US, Google subjected itself to the [**EU-US Privacy Shield**](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome). However, your IP address will be shortened prior to assessing usage statistics so that you cannot be identified. For this, Google Analytics uses the extension “anonymizeIP” on our website to ensure that IP addresses are collected anonymously.  
Google will process the information provided by the cookies to assess your use of this website, to compile reports about website activity and to perform additional services related to use of the website and the Internet.

As described above, you may configure your browser to reject cookies. You may also prevent the collection of cookie-generated data on your use of this website (incl. your IP address) and the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing a browser add-on provided by Google or, when accessing our website from a mobile device, activating this opt-out link: [**Deaktivieren Sie Google Analytics**](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). This will prevent the collection of data by Google Analytics on this website (the opt-out cookie will only work on the browser used and only for this domain). If you delete your cookies from this browser, you must activate this link again.  
For more information, please see [**Google's Privacy Policy**](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en).

2.2 Hotjar

Our website uses Hotjar, a web analysis service by Hotjar Ltd, Elia Zammit Street 3, St Julians STJ 1000, Malta ("Hotjar"). Hotjar is used to create heat maps. Heat Maps graphically display statistics about mouse movements and clicks on our site. This allows us to recognize frequently used functions on our website and to further improve the page. Hotjar uses cookies and similar technologies to analyze our website with regard to your user behavior. However, your IP address is shortened before the usage statistics are evaluated so that no conclusions can be drawn about your identity. In addition to mouse movements and clicks, information on the operating system, browser, incoming and outgoing links, geographical origin, resolution and type of device are evaluated for statistical purposes. This information is pseudonymous and will not be shared with third parties by us or Hotjar. Data entered by you in form fields on our website will be hidden and not collected by Hotjar.

The collection of data by Hotjar can be deactivated on all websites operated by us or other providers that use Hotjar through your objection (so-called opt-out). You will find more detailed explanations and a function to explain your objection on the [**Hotjar Opt-Out page**](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out). In addition, Hotjar supports the so-called Do-Not-Track function of your browser. If you enable this in your browser, Hotjar will not collect any data. You can find instructions for the different browsers on the Hotjar website. 

For more information, please refer to [**Privacy Policy von Hotjar**](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy).

IV. Transfer of personal data

The data we collect on you will only be transferred if:

• You provided your express consent 

• The transfer is required for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims and if there is no reason to believe that you have an overriding interest in the non-disclosure of your data,

• We are required by law to transfer your data or if

• Permitted by law and required for the performance of a contractual relationship with you or for pre-contractual measures requested by you.  
Furthermore, your personal data may be transferred if required by public authorities, court orders or legal proceedings if necessary for litigation or legal defense.  
Data processing may partially be performed by our service providers. In addition to the service providers stated in this Privacy Policy, this may especially include data centers, software providers (e.g., for log file management or sending newsletters), IT service providers, help desks, agencies, market research companies, group companies and consulting firms. If we transfer data to our service providers, the service providers may only use this data for the performance of their tasks. Service providers are diligently selected and commissioned by us. If these service providers process your data outside of the European Union, your data may be transferred to a country with lower data protection standards than in the European Union. For such cases, glomex ensures that the respective service providers guarantee an equal level of data protection (e.g., by concluding Standard Contractual Clauses with the service provider or through certification of the service provider under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield). You may receive copies of these guarantees from our Data Protection Officer (see Contact section above).

V. Storage Duration

We will only save your personal data for as long as required for the fulfillment of the contractual or legal obligations for which we collected your data. Afterwards, we will delete your data without delay, unless we need your data as evidence for civil law purposes or until the legal storage period expires. We are required to save your contract data as evidence for three years after the end of the year in which our business relationship with you ends. Any claims will expire at the earliest date permitted by the statute of limitations. However, we may have to save your data for longer for accounting or for other legally required purposes. We may be required to do so due to legal documentation obligations, e.g., under the German Commercial Code [Handelsgesetzbuch] or the German Fiscal Code [Abgabenordnung].

VI. Data subjects‘ rights

You have the right to receive information about the processing of your personal data by us at any time. We will explain the data processing to you and provide an overview of personal data saved on you by us. If personal data saved by us is inaccurate or no longer up to date, you have the right to rectification of this data. You also have the right to erasure of your data. You also have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data if, e.g., you contest the accuracy of the data. You also have the right to data portability, i.e., we will provide you with a digital copy of the personal data we saved on you if requested. You also have the right to object to data processing if based on our legitimate interests. Our newsletters include unsubscribe links. To exercise your rights described above, you may use the information in the Contact section above. Please make sure that we can clearly identify you.

You also have the right to submit complaints to our competent data protection supervisory authority (Bayerisches Landesamt für Datenschutzaufsicht - BayLDA, Promenade 27, D-91522 Ansbach poststelle@lda.bayern.de) or to the data protection authority of your habitual residence who will forward your inquiry to the competent authority. You may also withdraw any consent you provided for the processing of your personal data at any time with future effect without stating reasons. You may exercise your withdrawal right by contacting us via the information stated in the Contact section.

VII. Updates of the Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy was last updated in January 2019. Since we strive to continuously improve the protection of your data through our technical capabilities, we recommend viewing our Privacy Policy from time to time and informing yourself about any changes.

Annex: Technical Notes

Internet Explorer:

Mozilla Firefox:

Google Chrome:

Safari:
